Finding Aid for the Ralph J. Bunche papers LSC.2051
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Speeches, Interviews, and Broadcasted Recordings, 1926-1969; 54 boxes
  - "Human Relations - National and International," St. Paul Council of Human Relations, speech, 1954 January 18 (Box 362, Folder 10)
  - Lincoln Association, untitled speech, 1954 February 12 (Box 362, Folder 11)
  - "Our Opportunities for World Co-Operation," National Farm Institute, speech, 1954 February 20 (Box 362, Folder 12)
  - "The United Nations in World Focus," University of Maine, speech, 1954 February 25 (Box 362, Folder 13)
  - Abyssinian Baptist Church, Annual Layman's address, 1954 February 28 (Box 363, Folder 1)
  - Freedom Fulfillment Conference, NAACP, untitled address, 1954 March 10 (Box 363, Folder 2)
  - Bethune-Cookman College, speech, 1954 March 17 (Box 363, Folder 3)
  - Human Relations Conference, University of Illinois, untitled speech, 1954 March 24 (Box 363, Folder 4)
  - Model United Nations for High School Students, UN Council of Harvard, address, 1954 March 27 (Box 363, Folder 5)
  - "Is the United Nations Indispensable?" Young Women's Republican club of New York, luncheon remarks, 1954 March 31 (Box 363, Folder 6)
  - Ohio College Association, untitled address, 1954 April 3 (Box 363, Folder 7)
  - United Negro College Fund, untitled address, 1954 April 5 (Box 363, Folder 8)
  - "Races and the United Nations," Trinity Church in the City of New York, speech, 1954 April 6 (Box 363, Folder 9)
  - "For Such a Time as This," Scarsdale Congregation Church, speech, 1954 April 8 (Box 363, Folder 10)
  - "Background for Understanding the UN," Columbia University, speech, 1954 April 12 (Box 363, Folder 11)
  - Alliance for Political Affairs, Bryn Mawr College, speech, 1954 April 14 (Box 363, Folder 12)
  - "The United Nations and the World Crisis," Community Church of Boston, speech, 1954 April 18 (Box 363, Folder 13)
  - "Why the United Nations?" American Association of International Relations Clubs, address, 1954 April 19 (Box 363, Folder 14)
  - U.S. Military Academy, untitled lecture, 1954 April 20 (Box 363, Folder 15)
  - Grinnell College, untitled lecture, 1954 April 22 (Box 363, Folder 16)
  - "Human Relations in World Perspective," Fountain Club Conference, speech, 1954 April 24 (Box 363, Folder 17)
  - Pre-Campaign Rally, Cerebral Palsy of Queens, untitled speech, 1954 April 28 (Box 363, Folder 18)
  - "The United Nations and Colonial Peoples," Trenton Conference, New Jersey AAUN, speech, 1954 April 29 (Box 364, Folder 1)
  - New York State Political Science Association, untitled speech, 1954 May 1 (Box 364, Folder 2)
  - School of Business & Public Administration, Cornell University, untitled speech, 1954 May 3 (Box 364, Folder 3)
  - "Changing Dimensions of Diplomacy and National Representation," Washington Seminar on International Affairs, speech, 1954 May 6 (Box 364, Folder 4)
  - Oberlin Women's Club of New York, remarks, 1954 May 8 (Box 364, Folder 5)
  - "Human Relations in World Perspective," Dillard University, speech, 1954 May 9 (Box 364, Folder 6)
  - "Social Welfare - A World Concept," National conference of Social Work, speech, 1954 May 14 (Box 364, Folder 7)
  - Williamsburg Settlement Annual Dinner, remarks, 1954 May 16 (Box 364, Folder 8)
  - "How Necessary is the UN?" Laymen's Movement for a Christian World, speech, 1954 May 20 (Box 364, Folder 9)
  - University of Puerto Rico, commencement address, 1954 June 1 (Box 364, Folder 10)
  - Boston University, commencement address, 1954 June 6 (Box 364, Folder 11)
  - "Bread, Peace and Freedom," International Ladies Garment workers Union, speech, 1954 June 14 (Box 364, Folder 12)
  - Inter-Collegiate Leadership Institute, AAUN, remarks, 1954 June 21 (Box 364, Folder 13)
  - Omaha Centennial Interfaith program, untitled speech, 1953 June 26 (Box 364, Folder 14)
  - Annual Convention, National Education Association of the US, untitled address, 1954 June 30 (Box 365, Folder 1)
  - 45th Annual Convention, NAACP, address, 1954 July 4 (Box 365, Folder 2)
  - "Challenges to International Understanding," University of Toledo, speech, 1954 July 15 (Box 365, Folder 3)
  - Freedom Festival, untitled address, 1954 July 19 (Box 365, Folder 4)
  - "Challenges to International Understanding," University of Oregon, speech, 1954 July 20 (Box 365, Folder 5)
  - American Assembly, remarks (1 of 2), 1954 July 30 (Box 365, Folder 6)
  - American Assembly, remarks (2 of 2), 1954 July 30 (Box 365, Folder 7)
  - "The United Nations as Peacemaker," Chautauqua Lectures, speech (1 of 2), 1954 August 9 (Box 365, Folder 8)
  - "The United Nations as Peacemaker," Chautauqua Lectures, speech (2 of 2), 1954 August 9 (Box 365, Folder 9)
  - "The Challenge of Human Relations," Johns Hopkins University, speech, 1954 August 13 (Box 366, Folder 1)
  - Fifteenth Annual Meeting, American Political Science Association, Presidential address, 1954 September 9 (Box 366, Folder 2)
  - Fifteenth Annual Meeting, American Political Science Association, Presidential address excerpts, 1954 September 9 (Box 366, Folder 3)
  - Springfield College, convocation speech, 1954 September 26 (Box 366, Folder 4)
  - Jewish Memorial Hospital, Laboratory Dedication, remarks, 1954 October 3 (Box 366, Folder 5)
  - 13th Anniversary Dinner, Freedom House, remarks, 1954 October 3 (Box 366, Folder 6)
  - Eleanor Roosevelt's 70th Birthday, AAUN, remarks, 1954 October 11 (Box 366, Folder 7)
  - "United Nations as Peacemaker," UN Rally Week, speech, 1954 October 14 (Box 366, Folder 8)
  - New York Town Hall, lecture, 1954 October 23 (Box 366, Folder 9)
  - Medal of Honor, Theodore Roosevelt Association, acceptance speech, 1954 October 27 (Box 366, Folder 10)
  - Career Day, Pennsylvania State University, speech, 1954 November 4 (Box 366, Folder 11)
  - International House, Van Kleffens introduction, 1954 November 11 (Box 366, Folder 12)
  - Testimonial Luncheon, National Committee for Rural Schools, remarks, 1954 November 20 (Box 366, Folder 13)
  - Saint Francis Peace Award, Third Order of Saint Francis, acceptance speech, 1954 December 28 (Box 366, Folder 14)
  - Speaking Engagements Schedule, 1955 (Box 366, Folder 15)
  - Materials related to broadcast recordings, 1955 (Box 366, Folder 16)
  - Conference of Non-Governmental Organizations Interested in the Eradication of Prejudice and Discrimination, untitled speech, 1955 March 31 (Box 367, Folder 1)
  - Triennial Convention of the Young Women's Christian Association, address, 1955 April 23 (Box 367, Folder 2)
  - Fifth Conference of Non-Governmental Organizations Interested in Migration, statement, 1955 May 2 (Box 367, Folder 3)
  - Abilene Senior High School, untitled statement (1 of 2), 1955 June 21 (Box 367, Folder 4)
  - Abilene Senior High School, untitled statement (2 of 2), 1955 June 21 (Box 367, Folder 5)
  - San Francisco Rotary Club, luncheon remarks, 1955 June 21 (Box 367, Folder 6)
  - "The United Nations Role," Commerce High School, speech, 1955 June 24 (Box 367, Folder 7)
  - New York Summer Festival and Children's United World Art Foundation, remarks, 1955 August 2 (Box 367, Folder 8)
  - Flint Centennial Faith and Freedom Rally, untitled speech, 1955 September 4 (Box 367, Folder 9)
  - Young Adult Branch-Wide Conference Banquet, YMCA, dinner remarks, 1955 October 1 (Box 367, Folder 10)
  - Freedom House Dinner and Award, remarks, 1955 October 9 (Box 367, Folder 11)
  - AAUN Dinner in Honor of Danny Kaye, untitled speech, 1955 October 17 (Box 367, Folder 12)
  - "The United Nations After Ten Years," Columbia University, speech, 1955 October 24 (Box 367, Folder 13)
  - Pediatric Travel Club, remarks, 1955 November 5 (Box 367, Folder 14)
  - "Report Card," CBS broadcast, remarks, 1955 November 6 (Box 367, Folder 15)
  - "The United Nations and Peaceful Uses of Atomic Energy," International Press Institute, speech, 1955 November 7 (Box 367, Folder 16)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews, scripts, 1955 November 11 (Box 367, Folder 17)
  - "Basis for Understanding the United Nations," New York University, speech, 1955 November 17 (Box 367, Folder 18)
  - New York Bible Society, remarks, 1955 November 20 (Box 368, Folder 1)
  - Thirty-fifth Annual Meeting, National Council for the Social Studies,untitled statement, 1955 November 24 (Box 368, Folder 2)
  - American Pharmaceutical Manufacturer's Association, award presentation, remarks, 1955 December 13 (Box 368, Folder 3)
  - Speaking Engagement Schedule, 1956 (Box 368, Folder 4)
  - Materials related to broadcasted recordings, 1956 (Box 368, Folder 5)
  - Brotherhood Awards Dinner, untitled speech, 1956 January 10 (Box 368, Folder 6)
  - "The UN After its First Decade," Portland Town Hall, speech, 1956 January 15 (Box 368, Folder 7)
  - South Bend-Mishawaka International Relations Council, Central High School, speech, 1956 January 21 (Box 368, Folder 8)
  - Sinai Temple Lecture Forum, untitled speech, 1956 January 22 (Box 368, Folder 9)
  - Michigan Press Association, Michigan State University, address, 1956 January 27 (Box 368, Folder 10)
  - Dedication of Supreme Court Building, Puerto Rico, remarks, 1956 February 2 (Box 368, Folder 11)
  - Lincoln Bust Unveiling, Freedom House, remarks, 1956 February 9 (Box 368, Folder 12)
  - Fairleigh Dickinson College, honorary degree, acceptance speech, 1956 February 10 (Box 368, Folder 13)
  - High School of Music and Art, senior assembly, remarks, 1956 February 14 (Box 368, Folder 14)
  - University of Massachusetts, untitled speech, 1956 February 16 (Box 368, Folder 15)
  - "Peaceful Uses of Atomic Energy: Action Through the UN," UN Internes Lecture, 1956 February 17 (Box 368, Folder 16)
  - "The Issue of Colonialism," National War College, speech, 1956 February 21 (Box 368, Folder 17)
  - "Toward a Peaceful World," National Association of Secondary School Principals, speech, 1956 February 28 (Box 369, Folder 1)
  - Capahosic Conference, untitled remarks, 1956 March 3 (Box 369, Folder 2)
  - Great Issues Course, Dartmouth College, untitled speech, 1956 March 5 (Box 369, Folder 3)
  - Pi Sigma Alpha, Howard University, installation remarks, 1956 March 9 (Box 369, Folder 4)
  - "Colonialism in the World Today," University of North Carolina, speech, 1956 March 13 (Box 369, Folder 5)
  - Friars Club Testimonial Dinner, remarks, 1956 March 15 (Box 369, Folder 6)
  - Wilmington Branch, NAACP, untitled lecture, 1956 March 18 (Box 369, Folder 7)
  - "Human Rights and Freedom in the World," California High School Civil Liberties Conference, speech, 1956 March 24 (Box 369, Folder 8)
  - "The UN in Proper Perspective," YMCA-Leaders of America Program, speech, 1956 April 10 (Box 369, Folder 9)
  - "Expanding the Frontiers of Democracy," Modern Forum, speech, 1956 April 11 (Box 369, Folder 10)
  - "Toward a World Both Free and Peaceful," University of Arizona Auditorium, speech, 1956 April 15 (Box 369, Folder 11)
  - Celebration Lecture, University of New Mexico, untitled lecture, 1956 April 16 (Box 369, Folder 12)
  - "The UN in Proper Perspective," University of New Hampshire, speech, 1956 May 3 (Box 369, Folder 13)
  - "The Colonial Issue and the United Nations," Fisk-Hillman Lecture, Fisk University, speech, 1956 May 5 (Box 370, Folder 1)
  - Parents Night, Union Congregation Church, remarks, 1956 May 6 (Box 370, Folder 2)
  - "UN and Colonialism," Princeton University, lecture, 1956 May 7 (Box 370, Folder 3)
  - "The United Nations in its Second Decade," Washington University, speech, 1956 May 9 (Box 370, Folder 4)
  - "The United Nations in its Second Decade," Kansas State College, speech, 1956 May 10 (Box 370, Folder 5)
  - Mamaroneck High School, school assembly, 1956 May 16 (Box 370, Folder 6)
  - 10th Anniversary, Northside Center for Child Development, untitled speech, 1956 May 17 (Box 370, Folder 7)
  - 2nd Annual Dinner, NAACP Legal Defense and Educational Fund, script, 1956 May 17 (Box 370, Folder 8)
  - Lord & Taylor Award Luncheon, remarks, 1956 May 18 (Box 370, Folder 9)
  - "I Am An American Day Celebration," remarks, 1956 May 20 (Box 370, Folder 10)
  - 25th Birthday Dinner, Fellowship House, untitled speech, 1956 May 21 (Box 370, Folder 11)
  - Father of the Year Luncheon, remarks, 1956 May 24 (Box 370, Folder 12)
  - Ten Times One is Ten Club, Alabama State College, untitled speech, 1956 May 27 (Box 370, Folder 13)
  - Alabama Agricultural & Mechanical College, commencement address, 1956 May 28 (Box 370, Folder 14)
  - Doctor of Laws honorary degree, New York University, remarks, 1956 June 5 (Box 370, Folder 15)
  - "Toward a World Both Free and Peaceful," Depauw University, commencement address, 1956 June 10 (Box 370, Folder 16)
  - Oxford University, remarks, 1956 July 17 (Box 370, Folder 17)
  - Play Schools Association Luncheon, untitled speech, 1956 October 4 (Box 370, Folder 18)
  - "The World Significance of the Carver Story," Annual Christian Liberal Arts Festival, Simpson College, speech, 1956 October 6 (Box 370, Folder 19)
  - "Can the UN Maintain the Peace?" National War College, speech, 1956 December 13 (Box 371, Folder 1)
  - Speaking Engagement Schedule, 1957 (Box 371, Folder 2)
  - Materials related to broadcasted recordings, 1957 (Box 371, Folder 3)
  - "Removing Roadblocks to World Peace," World Brotherhood, WNYC radio broadcast, 1957 January 10 (Box 371, Folder 4)
  - University of Pittsburgh, commencement address, 1957 February 1 (Box 371, Folder 5)
  - Trusteeship Council, NGO Briefing, untitled speech, 1957 February 13 (Box 371, Folder 6)
  - Negro Actors Guild, remarks, 1957 February 20 (Box 371, Folder 7)
  - "The UN in the Near East: UNEF and SUEZ," University of Michigan, speech, 1957 April 20 (Box 371, Folder 8)
  - "The UN in the Near East: UNEF and SUEZ," Calvin Bullock Forum, speech, 1957 April 23 (Box 371, Folder 9)
  - "The UN in the Near East: UNEF and SUEZ," Duke University, speech, 1957 May 14 (Box 371, Folder 10)
  - "The UN in the Near East: UNEF and SUEZ," Stephens College, speech, 1957 May 18 (Box 371, Folder 11)
  - Oakwood School, commencement address, 1957 June 8 (Box 371, Folder 12)
  - Smith College, commencement address, 1957 June 9 (Box 371, Folder 13)
  - General Conference, International Atomic Energy Agency, statement, 1957 October 1 (Box 371, Folder 14)
  - "The UN Peace Effort in the Near East," Athenaeum of Summit, speech, 1957 November 14 (Box 371, Folder 15)
  - "The UN Peace Effort in the Near East," Ford Hall Forum, speech, 1957 December 1 (Box 371, Folder 16)
  - QANTAS, United Nations Headquarters, untitled speech, 1957 December 26 (Box 371, Folder 17)
  - Speaking Engagement Schedule, 1958 (Box 371, Folder 18)
  - Materials related broadcasted recordings, 1958 (Box 371, Folder 19)
  - Ground breaking ceremonies, Cerebral Palsy Center of Queens, remarks, 1958 January 12 (Box 371, Folder 20)
  - Arden House Conference, remarks, 1958 January 17 (Box 372, Folder 1)
  - Luncheon meeting, Rochester AAUN, remarks, 1958 January 25 (Box 372, Folder 2)
  - American Association of Colleges for Teachers Education, untitled speech, 1958 February 21 (Box 372, Folder 3)
  - Conference on Foreign Aspects of United States National Security, remarks, 1958 February 25 (Box 372, Folder 4)
  - "Race Relations - A World-wide View," Broadway Congregation Church, speech, 1958 March 16 (Box 372, Folder 5)
  - Freedom House Luncheon, remarks, 1958 April 7 (Box 372, Folder 6)
  - "Foreign Policy from the UN Perspective," Southern Methodist University, speech, 1958 April 8 (Box 372, Folder 7)
  - Luncheon meeting, Dallas AAUN, remarks, 1958 April 9 (Box 372, Folder 8)
  - Dedication of Bunche Junior High School, Compton Union High School District, speech, 1958 April 10 (Box 372, Folder 9)
  - Los Angeles City College, untitled speech, 1958 April 10-11 (Box 372, Folder 10)
  - "The UNEF: From Talk to Operation," Los Angeles World Affairs Council, luncheon remarks, 1958 April 11 (Box 372, Folder 11)
  - Lycoming College, commencement address, 1958 June 8 (Box 372, Folder 12)
  - Harlem Citizen's Committee of 100, introductory remarks for Dr. Kwame Nkrumah, 1958 July 27 (Box 372, Folder 13)
  - American Committee on Africa and NAACP, introductory remarks for Dr. Kwame Nkrumah, 1958 July 29 (Box 372, Folder 14)
  - "Toward Peace and Understanding Among Peoples," Norwegian Red Cross Week, address, 1958 September 6 (Box 372, Folder 15)
  - Unveiling of Plaque in Memory of Count Bernadotte, United Nations Headquarters, statement, 1958 September 17 (Box 372, Folder 16)
  - "United Nations Paramilitary Operations in the Middle East: New Instruments of Peace," Johns Hopkins University, speech (Box 372, Folder 17)
  - New York AAUN Luncheon, remarks, 1958 November 24 (Box 372, Folder 18)
  - New York Town Hall, Leipziger lecture, 1958 November 26 (Box 372, Folder 19)
  - Speaking Engagement Schedule, 1959 (Box 373, Folder 1)
  - Materials related to broadcasted recordings, 1959 (Box 373, Folder 2)
  - Albert Gallatin Associates Dinner, New York University, speech, 1959 January 28 (Box 373, Folder 3)
  - University of Pittsburgh, interview questions, 1959 February 2 (Box 373, Folder 4)
  - "Do We Need Permanent UN Emergency Forces?" New York Times Youth Forum, remarks, 1959 February 8 (Box 373, Folder 5)
  - Periclean Club Annual Forum, untitled speech, 1959 February 13 (Box 373, Folder 6)
  - "'Brotherhood' and the Realities," Washington University, speech, 1959 February 18 (Box 373, Folder 7)
  - Annual Brotherhood Award, Congregation B'nai Jeshurun, acceptance speech, 1959 February 21 (Box 373, Folder 8)
  - "Some Implications, National and International, of Our Problem of Race Relations," Wesleyan University Assembly Program, speech, 1959 February 23 (Box 373, Folder 9)
  - "The UN in the Near East Today," Springfield Adult Education Council, speech, 1959 March 4 (Box 373, Folder 10)
  - "United Nations: Power for World Peace," North Carolina AAUN, speech, 1959 March 18 (Box 373, Folder 11)
  - "Conditions and Prospects for Peace," North Carolina State College, speech, 1959 March 19 (Box 373, Folder 12)
  - "UN Military Operations for Peace," Haverford College, speech, 1959 March 24 (Box 373, Folder 13)
  - Introduction to film "Power Among Men," Museum of Modern Art, speech, 1959 March 26 (Box 373, Folder 14)
  - Friends General Conference, remarks, 1959 April 2 (Box 373, Folder 15)
  - Student Council Banquet, Howard University, untitled speech, 1959 April 4 (Box 373, Folder 16)
  - International Relations Program, Northwestern University, untitled speech, 1959 April 9 (Box 373, Folder 17)
  - "The UN's Contribution to 'Quiet' in the Middle East Today," University of Minnesota, speech, 1959 May 14 (Box 374, Folder 1)
  - Four Freedoms Foundation Dinner, remarks, 1959 May 26 (Box 374, Folder 2)
  - Prize Essay Competition, New York Chamber of Commerce, speech, 1959 June 3 (Box 374, Folder 3)
  - Dedication of Bust, UCLA Commencement, address, 1959 June 12 (Box 374, Folder 4)
  - Long Beach State College, commencement address, 1959 June 12 (Box 374, Folder 5)
  - "A Review of Selected Aspects of UN Activities," Long Beach AAUN, dinner remarks, 1959 June 12 (Box 374, Folder 6)
  - "The UN's Contribution to 'Quiet' in the Middle East Today," Santa Barbara AAUN, speech, 1959 July 19 (Box 374, Folder 7)
  - Introduction of Nnamdi Azikiwe, NAACP meeting, remarks, 1959 July 19 (Box 374, Folder 8)
  - "The Role of the United Nations in International Politics as Seen from its Headquarters in New York City," International Seminar for Diplomats, speech (Box 374, Folder 9)
  - "United Nations Treatment of Colonial Questions," Polish AUN, speech, 1959 August 16 (Box 374, Folder 10)
  - "The UN's Contribution to 'Quiet' in the Middle East Today," Austrian AUN, speech, 1959 September 29 (Box 374, Folder 11)
  - Detroit AUN, untitled speech, 1959 October 18 (Box 374, Folder 12)
  - Temple Israel Forum Series, untitled lecture, 1959 October 21 (Box 374, Folder 13)
  - Social Environment Symposium, Brown University, remarks (1 of 2), 1959 October 22 (Box 374, Folder 14)
  - Social Environment Symposium, Brown University, remarks (2 of 2), 1959 October 22 (Box 375, Folder 1)
  - Convocation, Ohio University, untitled speech, 1959 November 13 (Box 375, Folder 2)
  - "Some Current United Nations Contributions to Peace and Progress," University of Pennsylvania, lecture, 1959 December 10 (Box 375, Folder 3)
  - Speaking Engagement Schedule, 1960 (Box 375, Folder 4)
  - Materials related to broadcasted recordings, 1960 (Box 375, Folder 5)
  - Ohio Wesleyan University, untitled speech, 1960 February 7 (Box 375, Folder 6)
  - Symposium on Africa, Wellesley College, introductory remarks (1 of 2), 1960 February 16 (Box 375, Folder 7)
  - Symposium on Africa, Wellesley College, introductory remarks (2 of 2), 1960 February 16 (Box 375, Folder 8)
  - Annual Brotherhood Festival, Mid-Queens Community Council, speech, 1960 February 20 (Box 375, Folder 9)
  - Brandeis University, untitled speech, 1960 February 25 (Box 375, Folder 10)
  - "Prospects of Mankind," Brandeis University, television broadcast, 1960 March 6 (Box 375, Folder 11)
  - "Recent Middle East Developments Involving the UN," Center for Middle Eastern Studies, Harvard Foundation Council, speech, 1960 March 9 (Box 375, Folder 12)
  - Voice of America, statement, 1960 March 17 (Box 375, Folder 13)
  - House of Representatives, Legislature of the State of Hawaii, remarks, 1960 March 18 (Box 375, Folder 14)
  - "The United Nations Grows Steadily Stronger," Tokyo AUN, speech, 1960 March 21 (Box 375, Folder 15)
  - Japan-America Society, luncheon remarks, 1960 March 21 (Box 376, Folder 1)
  - "The UN as Peace Maker," Sankei Hall, speech, 1960 March 22 (Box 376, Folder 2)
  - "The United Nations Approach to the Underdeveloped Areas," International Cultural Association, speech, 1960 March 23 (Box 376, Folder 3)
  - "The United Nations and the Middle East," Fukuoka broadcast, speech, 1960 March 26 (Box 376, Folder 4)
  - "Emerging Africa and the United Nations," Osaka broadcast, speech, 1960 March 28 (Box 376, Folder 5)
  - "The United Nations Secretariat: The New International Civil Servant," Kansai AUN, speech, 1960 March 29 (Box 376, Folder 6)
  - Japan engagement schedule, includes remarks (1 of 2), 1960 March 21-29 (Box 376, Folder 7)
  - Japan engagement schedule, includes remarks (2 of 2), 1960 March 21-29 (Box 376, Folder 8)
  - Springfield Town Hall, untitled lecture, 1960 April 8 (Box 376, Folder 9)
  - Alton High School, untitled speech, 1960 April 9 (Box 376, Folder 10)
  - International Relations Course, United States Military Academy, untitled speech, 1960 April 14 (Box 376, Folder 11)
  - History Club, Choate School, remarks, 1960 April 17 (Box 376, Folder 12)
  - "Africa and the United Nations," Colby College, speech, 1960 April 18 (Box 376, Folder 13)
  - Conference on World Tensions, University of Chicago, untitled speech, 1960 May 11 (Box 376, Folder 14)
  - "Peace Prospects from the UN Perspective," John A. Ryan Forum, speech, 1960 May 13 (Box 377, Folder 1)
  - "Emergent Africa and the United Nations," University of Illinois, speech, 1960 May 17 (Box 377, Folder 2)
  - "Human Relations and World Tensions," Wayne State University, speech, 1960 May 19 (Box 377, Folder 3)
  - "A Commentary," Indiana State Teachers College, commencement address, 1960 May 29 (Box 377, Folder 4)
  - Circus Saints & Sinners Club, dinner remarks, 1960 September 27 (Box 377, Folder 5)
  - Federation of Nigeria, interview questions, 1960 November 14-18 (Box 377, Folder 6)
  - Annual Dinner, New York Cardiac Center, remarks, 1960 December 3 (Box 377, Folder 7)
  - "Exploding Africa, the United Nations and Peace," Marshall College, speech, 1960 December 10 (Box 377, Folder 8)
  - "The Challenge of Africa: Tensions and Moral Values," Brickner Memorial Lecture, Fairmont Temple, speech, 1960 December 14 (Box 377, Folder 9)